<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conference Talk on Jennifer Weir</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/conference-talk/</link><description>Recent content in Conference Talk on Jennifer Weir</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:02:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/conference-talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You Belong Here Too</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/you-belong-here-too/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/you-belong-here-too/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="young-first-gen-female-new-heres-why-you-belong-here-too">Young? First-Gen? Female? New? Here&amp;rsquo;s Why You Belong Here Too&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Engineering is hard. Tech is hard. Feeling like you don&amp;rsquo;t belong in these fields? Even harder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Identity Diversity can be divided into 2 categories: observable characteristsics and underlying characteristics. Observable characteristics are Age, Clothing or Style of Dress, Expressions or Mannerisms, Gender, Physical Ability, and Skin Color. Underlying characteristics are, Cultural Identity, Educational Background, Experience Level, Family Status, Socioeconomic Class, and Values &amp;amp; Beliefs. At some point in your life, you have likely walked into a room where someone made you feel uncomfortable due to some characteristic listed above. Sometimes, discomfort can be healthy and lead to personal growth; other times, it may be extreme enough to make you dissociate and wish you never walked into that room at all. It’s normal to feel this way when entering a new environment, but extreme discomfort becomes an issue when feelings of disconnection are prolonged, especially if these feelings affect how someone participates in social and professional interactions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>