<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Team-Building on Jennifer Weir</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/team-building/</link><description>Recent content in Team-Building on Jennifer Weir</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:02:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/team-building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You Belong Here Too</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/you-belong-here-too/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/you-belong-here-too/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="young-first-gen-female-new-heres-why-you-belong-here-too">Young? First-Gen? Female? New? Here&amp;rsquo;s Why You Belong Here Too&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Engineering is hard. Tech is hard. Feeling like you don&amp;rsquo;t belong in these fields? Even harder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Identity Diversity can be divided into 2 categories: observable characteristsics and underlying characteristics. Observable characteristics are Age, Clothing or Style of Dress, Expressions or Mannerisms, Gender, Physical Ability, and Skin Color. Underlying characteristics are, Cultural Identity, Educational Background, Experience Level, Family Status, Socioeconomic Class, and Values &amp;amp; Beliefs. At some point in your life, you have likely walked into a room where someone made you feel uncomfortable due to some characteristic listed above. Sometimes, discomfort can be healthy and lead to personal growth; other times, it may be extreme enough to make you dissociate and wish you never walked into that room at all. It’s normal to feel this way when entering a new environment, but extreme discomfort becomes an issue when feelings of disconnection are prolonged, especially if these feelings affect how someone participates in social and professional interactions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unreasonable Hospitality Part 1</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/unreasonable-hospitality-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 02:32:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/unreasonable-hospitality-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book Review! I love non-fiction. I love hearing (or reading) people&amp;rsquo;s stories. I love when a non-fiction piece is a true page turner. Most of all, I love when something read in a book lines up with life in such a way that feels as if the author &lt;strong>knew&lt;/strong> it was meant for you. Partly great book buying by the consumer, partly great book recommending by a friend (or algorithm), or maybe, they&amp;rsquo;re a very good author capable of targeting a wide audience. All wins!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Better Teams</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/building-better-teams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 01:39:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/building-better-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p>In school, I had a band teacher who used to say, &amp;ldquo;How do you get a better band? You get better players&amp;rdquo;. While there is surely some truth to this concept (orchestras hire musicians with the best auditions and companies work to attract graduates from top universities), pure talent and skill will only get us so far. Realistically, this concept only applies to niche fields where people have characteristics that make them inherently better at some particular thing (being 7 feet tall and good at basketball comes to mind). Otherwise, the idea of &amp;ldquo;to get better, you have to simply be better&amp;rdquo; has diminishing returns when each individual is considered an average (or slightly better than average) performer on their own. At some point, an extra sliver of excellence in any one individual is insignificant in everyday life and irrelevant when trying to build better teams (similar to how studying 4 extra hours to get a 98% instead of a 95% on the exam is likely not worth your time).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interdisciplinarity</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/interdisciplinarity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 14:48:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/interdisciplinarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Interdisciplinarity is a pretty neat concept that I was exposed to during an undergraduate research project in college. Specifically, assignments that surrounded the idea of &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinarity in a world of boxes&amp;rdquo;. While the idea did not have huge impact on my work at the time, I found myself returning to it as a solution that always seemed to &amp;ldquo;just work&amp;rdquo; for projects later on &amp;ndash; introducing a new, valuable set of additional solutions every time. Interdisciplinarity weaves in local politics when you would otherwise only be focused on constructing a new highway next to a small town, it weaves in hurtful stereotypes when you would otherwise only be focused on building a new social media app, and it considers all parties viewpoints while signing an engineering contract, not after the fact.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Business &amp; Engineering</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/business-engineering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 02:46:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/business-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;p>From grade school to higher education, business and engineering an treated as separate subjects. In general, they are separate because &amp;ldquo;business people don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>need&lt;/em> to know engineering concepts and engineers should just focus on engineering&amp;rdquo;, right? This is a typical argument for separation of duties &amp;ndash; why do people &lt;em>need to know&lt;/em> how the other thing works if they can be really good at one thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the real world, we see business and engineering become increasingly intertwined as problems become complex. Realistically, these two subjects are extremely reliant on each other because &lt;em>people are complex&lt;/em>. From a corporate perspective, engineering needs to be funded and business doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen unless there is some (typically engineered in some way) product to exchange. In every case, people are consumers of these types of transactions. Corporate organizational structures assign eccentric titles and positions, divide departments, and restructure responsibilities in an attempt to make sense of these complex systems; however, there is a common denominator in every case: business and engineering are treated as separate entities until it really matters to treat them as one.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>