<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jennifer Weir</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/authors/jennifer-weir/</link><description>Recent content on Jennifer Weir</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 02:46:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jenniferpweir.com/authors/jennifer-weir/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Business &amp; Engineering</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/09/05/business-engineering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 02:46:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/09/05/business-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;p>From grade school to higher education, business and engineering an treated as separate subjects. We aren&amp;rsquo;t taught they are mutually exclusive but in general, they are separate because business people don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>need&lt;/em> to know engineering concepts and engineers &lt;em>should&lt;/em> just focus on engineering. This is a typical argument for separation of duties &amp;ndash; why do people &lt;em>need to know&lt;/em> how the other thing works if they can be really good at one thing?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Why?</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/08/28/my-why/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:16:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/08/28/my-why/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In college, I was a member of the Internal Relations Committee for GEECS (Girls in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science) at the University of Michigan. For 4 semesters, I helped plan internal events and wrote blog posts that were shared in a distribution list to members of the org. With each post, I learned a lot about writing for an audience and gained valuable feedback that helped me craft future applications, proposals, and competition submissions for various professional events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Why?</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/08/28/my-why/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:16:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/08/28/my-why/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In college, I was a member of the Internal Relations Committee for GEECS (Girls in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science) at the University of Michigan. For 4 semesters, I helped plan internal events and wrote blog posts that were shared in a distribution list to members of the org. With each post, I learned a lot about writing for an audience and gained valuable feedback that helped me craft future applications, proposals, and competition submissions for various professional events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hardest 2 Weeks of the Semester</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/12/05/the-hardest-2-weeks-of-the-semester/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/12/05/the-hardest-2-weeks-of-the-semester/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/post-weekend-of-dec-3rd">https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/post-weekend-of-dec-3rd&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I never thought too deeply about these last two weeks of the semester…until I saw a certain TikTok over Thanksgiving break. This TikTok was one of many that I would soon see about college students talking and joking that these were the hardest 2 weeks of the semester. Yes, I have been a college student for 3 years now but I never thought any differently about these last 2 weeks until this year. Honestly, I thought the TikToks were over-exaggerated and funny, and I didn’t think they really related to me. Well, I was wrong.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Navigating a Difficult Binary (not 1s and 0s)</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/11/08/navigating-a-difficult-binary-not-1s-and-0s/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/11/08/navigating-a-difficult-binary-not-1s-and-0s/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/navigating-a-difficult-binary-not-1s-and-0s">https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/navigating-a-difficult-binary-not-1s-and-0s&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Professional success versus personal fulfillment. This perceived binary serves as an obstacle many women face and unfortunately cannot avoid. You might have thought about it before and if you identify as a woman I’m almost entirely sure it has crossed your mind. The main point is it doesn’t have to be one or the other, you can and should have both professional success and personal fulfillment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lately my favorite book genre has been memoirs. Over the past summer I read Michelle Obama’s “Becoming” and then Sheryl Sandberg’s “Lean In: Women, Work, and the Will to Lead”. If you are interested in how two influential women navigated work life balance I highly suggest them both. For a quicker introduction with great explanations, I suggest Sandberg’s 14 minute TED talk (because who doesn’t love TED talks). It’s from 2010 but, in my opinion, everything she says is still extremely relevant. Seriously, even if you stop reading now, go watch the video–you won’t regret it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No Need to Rush or Win the Race</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/04/10/no-need-to-rush-or-win-the-race/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/04/10/no-need-to-rush-or-win-the-race/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/no-need-to-rush-or-win-the-race">https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/no-need-to-rush-or-win-the-race&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s just “get through this next week” or “finish this homework” or “study for that exam”. As we approach the end of the semester I wanted to take a moment to recognize it is super easy to think like this and I wanted to acknowledge we are all victims to these thoughts. In all honesty, I feel like I’ve been taught to think like this my entire life. First it was wanting to move on to junior high, then “if only high school would start sooner”, and now I’m in college and it&amp;rsquo;s like, well, what is next? We are taught to get through the day, get through the week, and get through the semester. I feel myself constantly saying “lets get through it” without saying anything about how amazing these life events are. Feeling like everything is rushed is something I’ve thought about before but it never felt like there was anything I could do about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>March 13th, 2020</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/03/13/march-13th-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2022/03/13/march-13th-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/march-13th-2020">https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/march-13th-2020&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Friday, March 13th marks the day two years ago that was my last day of high school and I know it was the last normal day of school for many of you too. Let’s just say a lot has changed…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we know, COVID impacted everyone and some were affected more than others, losing loved ones and friends. We can never forget that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, many people were affected in less tangible ways, feeling the most vulnerable they have felt in their entire life. I know I was one of these people. Missing prom, not having a real graduation, and having an entirely online first year of college are still things I think about. It felt like one thing after the other was getting erased from my experiences that I felt were so concrete for so long. If you can relate in one way or another, I’m sure you feel the same way too. With so many awful things happening during a pandemic, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to think that these things matter. All I can say is these things matter too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Community Within GEECS</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2021/11/21/community-within-geecs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2021/11/21/community-within-geecs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/community-within-geecs">https://www.geecsumich.com/blog/community-within-geecs&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You belong here. Read that again. If you are new to CS, it is really easy to convince yourself that you are not good enough but remember, you are here for a reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I made the switch to CS early this semester and joined GEECS. After an online freshman year due to COVID, I finally felt like I found my community here on campus and if that is something you are struggling with, I hope you can find your community within GEECS too.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>