<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New on Jennifer Weir</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/new/</link><description>Recent content in New on Jennifer Weir</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:21:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/new/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consistency</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/10/25/consistency/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:21:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/10/25/consistency/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a practitioner of yoga, or in other words, a yogi. I like to go to classes twice a week when it&amp;rsquo;s cold outside and typically take most of the summer off to do outdoor activities in place of yoga when the weather is nice. Around this time of year, I adore picking back up with yoga and recognize what a gift it is to be able to continue with a consistent schedule. My personal favorite is seeing new faces attend a hot vinyasa, especially this time of year and into the new year. After years of an on-again, off-again yoga practice due to living in different places and a busy school schedule, being able to attend yoga classes consistently post-grad is so special, particularly when I think back to my first class years ago and realize how its transformative impact still stays with me today&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unreasonable Hospitality Part 1</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/10/13/unreasonable-hospitality-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 02:32:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/10/13/unreasonable-hospitality-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book Review! I love non-fiction. I love hearing (or reading) people&amp;rsquo;s stories. I love when a non-fiction piece is a true page turner. Most of all, I love when something read in a book lines up with life in such a way that feels as if the author &lt;strong>knew&lt;/strong> it was meant for you. Partly great book buying by the consumer, partly great book recommending by a friend (or algorithm), or maybe, they&amp;rsquo;re a very good author capable of targeting a wide audience. All wins!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>