<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New on Jennifer Weir</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/new/</link><description>Recent content in New on Jennifer Weir</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:02:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jenniferpweir.com/tags/new/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You Belong Here Too</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/11/08/you-belong-here-too/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/11/08/you-belong-here-too/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="young-first-gen-female-new-heres-why-you-belong-here-too">Young? First-Gen? Female? New? Here&amp;rsquo;s Why You Belong Here Too&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Engineering is hard. Tech is hard. Feeling like you don&amp;rsquo;t belong in these fields? Even harder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Identity Diversity can be divided into 2 categories: observable characteristsics and underlying characteristics. Observable characteristics are Age, Clothing or Style of Dress, Expressions or Mannerisms, Gender, Physical Ability, and Skin Color. Underlying characteristics are, Cultural Identity, Educational Background, Experience Level, Family Status, Socioeconomic Class, and Values &amp;amp; Beliefs. At some point in your life, you have likely walked into a room where someone made you feel uncomfortable due to some characteristic listed above. Sometimes, discomfort can be healthy and lead to personal growth; other times, it may be extreme enough to make you dissociate and wish you never walked into that room at all. It’s normal to feel this way when entering a new environment, but extreme discomfort becomes an issue when feelings of disconnection are prolonged, especially if these feelings affect how someone participates in social and professional interactions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Consistency</title><link>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/10/25/consistency/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:21:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jenniferpweir.com/blog/2025/10/25/consistency/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a practitioner of yoga, or in other words, a yogi. I like to go to classes twice a week when it&amp;rsquo;s cold outside and typically take most of the summer off to do outdoor activities in place of yoga when the weather is nice. Around this time of year, I adore picking back up with yoga and recognize what a gift it is to be able to continue with a consistent schedule. My personal favorite is seeing new faces attend a hot vinyasa, especially this time of year and into the new year. After years of an on-again, off-again yoga practice due to living in different places and a busy school schedule, being able to attend yoga classes consistently post-grad is so special, particularly when I think back to my first class years ago and realize how its transformative impact still stays with me today.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>